

 $\searrow$ 

adakibet@gmail.com



+254 745 311-001



Nairobi, Kenya



adakibet.dev



linkedin.com/in/ada-kibet-877338189



github.com/ada-k



medium.com/@adakibet

### **SKILLS**

Python R Ma

TensorFlow

Nubcitow

ScikitLearn

Pylorch

Bert

Linux

Django

,





Kubarnatas



Numpy

Bash

Keras MongoDB

Tableau

Power BI

# **PROJECTS**

D.L Architectures

Language Modeling

Spatial Modeling

Graph Theory

Financial Modeling

# Adah Kibet

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer ready for remote work or relocation with 3+ years of experience working in Bio Tech, AI, Ed Tech and Software companies using Python, R and Matlab. I have a keen interest in research and combining it with engineering implementations to develop products and create informative, decisive and sustainable analytical and production workflows.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Member Board of Trustees**

10 Academy

04/2022 - Present

Santa Clara, United States (Remote)

Approval of the annual activity plan, budget and financial reports.

### **Data Scientist**

Pivot Bio.

02/2021 - 05/2022

Berkeley, USA. (Remote).

- Automated checks for microbial strains survival by building a 91% accurate CNN time-series classification model using TensorFlow.
- Conducted Power Analyses to inform experimental designs for microbial and field trials.
- Led the Data Engineering support team. Built ETL pipelines using SQL, Spark, Pandas and Hadoop.
- Disqualified the validity of satellite imagery in detecting product effect by bagging bayesian mixed-effect regressors for 300 field trials point data in Python, R and QGIS.
- Automated generation of reports on the status of data in the warehouse by building a python library.
- Set satellite imagery streaming and analysis pipelines through automated API calls from Planet and Descartes Labs in Python.
- Designed, prototyped, implemented, evaluated and deployed a Lidar Toolkit app in Flask and Bash.

# Machine Learning and Conversational AI Engineer

Traits Al.

01/2021 - 08/2021

San Diego, USA (Remote).

- Researched, built, trained, tested, optimised and deployed the FastSpeech2 Text to Speech Conversational AI model using RNNS and GANS in PyTorch on distributed GPU clusters.
- Researched, built and trained the Synthesize Obama Speech to Video model in PyTorch and Scikit Learn on AWS EC2 instances. Used AWS S3 as the data store.
- Optimised loss functions through hyperparameters tuning with the aid of a TensorBoard.

#### **Data Science Intern**

10 Academy

06/2020 - 10/2020

Berlin, Germany (Remote)

- Quantified the impact of the COVID-19 Kenyan government policy interventions by performing change point analysis using Python's Theano and Pymc3
- Built and deployed a pharmaceutical sales forecasting and analysis web app using Python and Heroku.
  Used a Random Forest Regression model with an MSE of 0.019 for the forecasting.
- Quantified the impact of an Ad-campaign on brand awareness by performing classical and sequential AB testing. The analysis concluded an awareness lift of 1.2%.
- Analysed users' experience, engagement and satisfaction of a telecommunications company to check for growth opportunities and make recommendation on whether it is worth buying or selling.
- Quantified the impact of Covid-19 lock down policies on air quality by performing Sentiment Analysis, Topic Modeling and Time Series Analysis on Twitter data. Used Python's tweepy, spacy, nltk.

# **Software Engineering Intern**

Swahili Box Hub.

04/2019 - 10/2019

Mombasa, Kenya.

- Designed, built and deployed a Marine Biome management web app using Django, JS and PostgreSQL.
- □ Integrated GitHub CI/CD into the development lifecycle.

### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Sc Mathematics and Computer Science.**

Technical University of Mombasa.

09/2016 - 02/2021

2nd Class Honors, Upper Division.